Now we can only trust them
Сейчас нам остаётся полагаться только на них
Your Highness
Ваше Высочество
The western neighbor seems to be moving
У западных соседей подозрительная активность
How can Your Highness suppress this news
Как Ваше Высочество можете скрывать это
And not let His Majesty recall troops to defend
и не дать императору отступить для защиты
Minister Xue
Господин Сюэ
Father has planned this battle for half his life
Отец готовился к этой битве полжизни
You have no solid evidence
У вас нет доказательств
How can I issue such an order?
как я могу дать такой приказ
We're not afraid of the unlikely
Лучше перестраховаться
But the one in ten thousand, Your Highness
чем потом сожалеть Ваше Высочество
If we wait for solid evidence before sending troops
Если ждать доказательств чтобы послать войска
Wouldn't it be too late?
не будет ли уже поздно
Your Highness is considerate of the Emperor
Вы щадите императора
But now the country's defenses are empty
но сейчас страна беззащитна
If the enemy truly invades
Если враг вторгнется
And we suffer defeat
и мы потерпим поражение
Will His Majesty be considerate of Your Highness?
станет ли император снисходителен
There were heavy rains in the southern border
В Южных землях прошли дожди
Which reduced your embezzlement by a bit
и вы получили меньше наживы
So you can't do this job anymore?
теперь вы не хотите работать
Minister Xue, do you think I'm young and easy to bully
Господин Сюэ считает что я молод и меня можно обмануть
And know nothing?
что я ничего не знаю
Your Highness, everything I do is for Great Xuan
Ваше Высочество я всё делаю ради Сюань
Your servant is willing to remonstrate with death
Готов умереть чтобы убедить вас
Minister Xue, you mustn't
Господин Сюэ нельзя же так
Your Highness
Ваше Высочество
We cannot treat Great Xuan's fate as a game
Судьба Сюань не игрушка
Lady Chen, what brings you here?
Госпожа Чэнь что вы здесь делаете
Since Minister Xue wants to remonstrate with death
Раз уж господин Сюэ хочет умереть помогите ему
Go help him
помогите ему
Yes
Слушаемся
Chen Wan'er
Чэнь Ваньэр
You
Ты
You dare kill a senior minister in the Taiji Hall
Ты осмелилась убить министра в зале Тайцзи
Do you really think His Majesty will tolerate you later?
Ты думаешь император тебя простит
Whether he tolerates me
Простит он меня или нет
Is a matter between His Majesty and me as husband and wife
это дело между мной и моим мужем императором
You're old
Старик в такие годы
Still so nosy
всё ещё такой любопытный
The Crown Prince is overseeing the court
Наследный принц в столице
His Majesty is personally leading the campaign
император лично возглавляет войска
My son has the courage to fight on the front lines
Мой сын сражается на фронте не дрогнув
The Chen family is not panicking
Семья Чэнь не в панике
Gentlemen
а вы господа
What are you panicking about?
чего испугались
The decisive battle between Great Xuan and Wuzhao
Решающая битва между Сюань и Уну
Is in these few days
произойдет в ближайшие дни
You gentlemen shall stay in the palace as guests
Господа останутся во дворце
I will personally host you
а я лично вас приму
Before the battle is settled
Пока исход войны не решён
Anyone who passes through this gate
любой кто осмелится покинуть этот зал
Kill
будет убит
Those who speak cunningly of retreat
Кто заговаривает об отступлении
Those who harm the state for personal gain
Кто во имя личной выгоды навредит стране
Yes
Слушаемся
Raise my royal banner in the formation
Вонзите моё знамя в центр поля
Send all the imperial guard
Отправьте туда весь отряд императорской стражи
Today
Сегодня
We must not let him escape
ни один из них не должен уйти
Yes
Слушаемся
Imperial Guard
Императорская гвардия
Follow me and kill
За мной в атаку
Kill
Вперёд
Sikong Yao
Сыкун Яо
Today is the life-and-death battle between you and me
сегодня наша с тобой смертельная схватка
Report
Донесение
My King
Ваш величество
Something's wrong
Беда
Xuan troops are attacking from behind
войска Сюань атакуют с тыла
Cutting off our retreat
отрезали нам пути к отступлению
What?
Что
Follow me to cut off their retreat
За мной Перережем им пути к отступлению
Brother
Брат
Let's retreat
Давай отступим
I fell into an ambush
Это я попал в засаду
This time, I fell into an ambush
На этот раз я попал в засаду
Let's regroup
Мы перегруппируемся
Brother
Брат
If not for you, for your son
Если бы не ты ради своего сына
Not following my orders
не послушал моего приказа
And engaging the enemy on your own
самовольно пошел на врага
How could we have come to this today?
как бы мы дошли до этого сегодня
Brother
Брат
Don't
Не
My empire was destroyed by you
Мои мечты о великом господстве разрушены тобой
Brother
Брат
Recall the vanguard
Отозвать передовой отряд
Break through from the rear
Прорываться через тыл
Yes
Слушаемся